<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<chapter version="5.0"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook http://www.docbook.org/xml/5.0/xsd/docbook.xsd http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink http://www.docbook.org/xml/5.0/xsd/xlink.xsd"
         xml:base="./" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:ns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
    <title>Emergency Service Introduction</title>
    <section>
        <title>Why Emergency Services?</title>
        
        <para>
            The Emergency Service Application was built as a blue print for architect applications using 
            the Drools and jBPM5 platform. The main goal of this application is to show how we can model and implement 
            a complete and complex business scenarios using the declarative power of: 
            Business Rules, Business Process and Complex Event Processing. Emergency Services is not just a simple example about
            how to integrate these tecnologies and approaches, we are aiming to build a complete scenario that can be used
            as a reference implementation. We want to build something real, something that scales for real usage, something 
            that you can use and map your business scenarios to and most important something that we can use to 
            teach new people about these amazing technologies.
        </para>
        <para>
            From the technical point of view, this application shows how components like a Rule Engine and 
            Business Process Engine can be integrated with technologies that are widely used in most system architectures. 
            Components -- like Distributed Caches, Transactional Frameworks, Messaging Systems, Web Services 
            Stacks and Web Frameworks -- can be combined to work around the declarative power of rules, processes and events.
        </para>
        <para>
            We want to go one step further and that's why this document tries to illustrate some principles and decisions that 
            we need to make in order to build applications that uses rules engines, process engines and event processing agents 
            with more traditional components.
        </para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Application Scope, Domain and Requirements</title>
        <para>
            The application was created to represent complex scenarios that are being executed by an Emergency Services 
            company that deals with concurrent emergencies within a city. The company needs to solve different situations 
            where different entities need to be coordinated to deal with an emergency situation. 
        </para>
        <para>
            The Emergency Services Application shows how we can provide a tool that helps the company to improve their services 
            by giving them full visibility of their actions, traceability of their resources, suggestions and advice based on 
            the context without sacrificing any degree of flexibility that they need to solve real life situations. One of the most 
            important requirements of the application is related to the the fact that most of the emergencies can be classified 
            under different categories based on their characteristics. We can model guidelines to solve each of these categories 
            but in real life, each emergency will be treated differently, depending on the context, the state of the company and 
            their resources. For each particular situation, different actions will be evaluated, suggested and executed. 
        </para>
       
        <para>
            To design the application we gather, understand and formalize the knowledge that the company experts use to drive 
            their activities.  The formalization of this knowledge will be introduced in the following sections where the Business 
            Processes, Business Rules and Events modeled for this application are described. 
        </para>
    </section>
    
    <section>
        <title>Scenario High Level Overview</title>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="images/city.png" format="PNG"/>
            </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
        <para> In order to understand the application requirements we need to understand the context
            in which the company operates. The following sections will describe the entities,
            vehicles and resources that interacts in order to deal with different emergencies. You
            will notice that the situations are being described using a business perspective without
            including technical terminology. This fact will allow us to validate with non technical
            people the application requirements, helping you to decouple the implementation from the
            concrete business scenario. 
            Each entity described will handle a limited set of resources that will affect the context of the
            company and the entities that are being coordinated.
            The size of the city and the amout of entities were selected for demonstration purposes. Using this reduced
            amount of entities allow us to show the concepts in action without increasing the application complexity. 
        </para>
    </section> 
    <section>
        <title>911 Building - Emergency Service Company</title>
        <para> The orange building located in the bottom left corner
            (911 building) will be in charge of dealing with the emergencies that happens within the
            city. This building represent the main entity from the application perspective, it
            represents all the employees and resources working to deal with multiple emergencies.
            The 911 building will also have the responsability to dispatch ambulances to quickly
            deal with emergencies that include injured people. 
        </para>
        <para>
            
        </para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="images/entity-911.png" format="PNG"/>
            </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
        <para> 
            Each ambulance will be monitored at all times, using a gps device that will allow us to see
            where the ambulance is and how far away from the emergency it is. Once the ambulance pick up the 
            patient from the emergency location, we will start recieving the patient vital signs. 
            For more information about the GPS tracking and Patient Vital Sign monitoring go to: [link here].
            Analyzing this information in real time will allow us to generate alerts and react if something
            goes wrong with the patient inside the ambulance. We can also push all the information to the
            related hospitals to keep them posted with the latest status.
        </para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="images/vehicle-ambulance.png" format="PNG"/>
            </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
    
    <section>
        <title>Hospitals</title>
        <para>
            We have three hospitals in this city. The hospital will be in charge of accepting injured people. Each hospital
            will be in charge of notifying the available beds and their opperating specialities, so the emergency services company can 
            plan and coordinate this entities.
            
        </para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="images/entity-hospital.png" format="PNG"/>
            </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Fire Fighters Deparment</title>
        <para>
            We just have one fire fighter deparment in this city. This entity will be in charge of dispatching fire trucks
            when we need to deal with a fire situation. This entity will be also responsible to fill the fire truck's water tank.            
        </para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="images/entity-firefighters.png" format="PNG"/>
            </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
        <para>
            Fire Trucks, as ambulances, will be tracked via GPS and we will be able to monitor from the central the water tanks level
            and the water pump heat status. This will allow us to notify the fire deparment so the can plan better how they provision,
            different fire trucks depending the emervency severity.
        </para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="images/vehicle-firetruck.png" format="PNG"/>
            </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Police Deparment</title>
        <para>
            We just have one police deparment in this city. This entity will be in charge of dispatching police cars
            when we need police intervention. This entity will be also responsible to host prisioners when is needed.             
        </para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="images/entity-policedeparment.png" format="PNG"/>
            </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
        <para>
            All the dispatched police cars will be tracked via GPS, and the police officers inside the car will be
            responsible to send updated information to the central about the emergency situation as soon as they arrive.
        </para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="images/vehicle-policecar.png" format="PNG"/>
            </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Emergency Types</title>
        <para>
            Based on the different situations that the company is prepared to deal with, and based on the entities that 
            the company can coordinate, they have defined a set of standard procedures that describe the most common
            set of activities that needs to be executed for each of this categories.
        </para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="images/emergency-types.png" format="PNG"/>
            </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
        <para>
            The following chapter will explain how based on these emergency types, the company define a set of procedures and 
            how we will formalize them using business rules, business processes and events. Then section X will describe the 
            implementation details for each of these procedures. Section Y will describe which mechanism needs to be implemented
            to provide flexibility to support a wide range of situations where none of the standard procedures fits one hundread 
            percent.
        </para>
    </section>
    
</chapter>
