<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<chapter version="5.0"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook http://www.docbook.org/xml/5.0/xsd/docbook.xsd http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink http://www.docbook.org/xml/5.0/xsd/xlink.xsd"
         xml:base="./" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:ns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
    <title>Emergency Service - Knowledge Representation</title>
    <section>
        <title>Declarative Knowledge Representation</title>
        <para>
            The application uses the concept of procedure to define the set of business processes, 
            business rules and domain specific services that will be used to deal with an emergency. 
            We have defined a set of default procedures that describe the activities that can be executed 
            during specific emergencies. The “Default Heart Attack Procedure” can be used to drive a standard 
            set of activities that needs to be executed each time a person suffers a heart attack. The “Default 
            Fire Emergency Procedure” describes the same but for emergencies that include fire situations where we 
            need to coordinate the firefighters department in order to mitigate the dangerous situation 
            as soon as possible. 
        </para>
        <para>
            Both procedures set up the basic activities that the company needs to execute in each specific 
            situation, but in no way do they limit the company to add, remove or execute more activities in parallel.
        </para>
        <para>
            Before executing these procedures, the company needs to identify the context of the emergency by 
            executing a set of activities that were designed to pick up the initial information and find out 
            what is happening. These activities are contained in a Generic Emergency Procedure that is executed 
            each time the phone rings in the central offices. 
        </para>
      
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Generic Emergency Procedure</title>
        <para>This procedure will initiate the information about an emergency and is based on the initial information that 
            is being gathered by the phone operators of the company. Using this information, a suggestion mechanism based 
            on Business Rules will be in charge of suggesting the most appropriate, specific procedures out of all the 
            available procedures.   
            
            This generic procedure is driven by the following business process:
        </para>
        <figure>
            <title>Generic Emergency Procedure</title>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata fileref="images/GenericEmergencyProcedure.png" format="PNG"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        <para>
            The Suggest Emergency Procedures activity inside this business process uses a set of rules to analyze the context 
            of the emergency gathered to suggest a set of procedures that fits with that specific situation. These rules will 
            evaluate the status of the company in order to suggest viable procedures. 
        </para>    
        <para>    
            Once the Suggestion rules are executed, the control expert in charge reviews the suggestions and modifies or 
            approves the selected procedures. The business process automatically will start each selected procedure in 
            parallel and it will wait until it receives a notification that all the specific procedures have ended. 
        </para>
        <para> 
            The main purpose of this generic procedure is to speed up the activities that need to be executed for every 
            emergency that the central offices handle. The suggestion rules help the experts by giving them a clear 
            set of procedures that can be executed based on the current status of the company and also on the contextual 
            and semantic information gathered for each specific situation. Once the procedures are started, a separate 
            group of resources will be used to monitor all the activities executed for each emergency.
        </para>
        
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Heart Attack Procedure</title>
        <para>
            As soon as we identify a heart attack situation, the system will automatically suggest to the expert which 
            procedures best fit based on contextual information. If the Default Heart Attack Procedure is selected, 
            the activities described by the following business process will be executed:
        </para> 
        <figure>
            <title>Heart Attack Emergency Procedure</title>
             <mediaobject>
                 <imageobject>
                     <imagedata fileref="images/DefaultHeartAttackProcedureSinglePatient.png" format="PNG"/>
                 </imageobject>
             </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        <para>
            This sequence of activities and events defines exactly how the company must deal with a Heart Attack situation.
            Briefly, an ambulance will be selected according to the company status and the patient information and it will 
            be dispatched to the emergency location. Once that ambulance arrives, the Doctor will send an updated report 
            to the central about the situation. This information will be correlated with the emergency location, 
            the location of different hospitals based on distance, and the availability of the health-care services 
            in each hospital to select the most appropriate facility. Once the patient is at the hospital, a report 
            about this procedure will be created. 
        </para>
        <para>
            This business process is enriched by different sets of rules that are being executed in different 
            activities to take automated actions to speed up the service and the human involvement times. 
            For this particular use case, a set of rules is being defined to automatically select the best 
            hospital based on the available information.  Taking advantage of the Complex Event Process 
            features provided by the platform, another group of rules are defined to take care of more dynamic 
            and reactive aspects that need to be covered. 
            
            The following rule is one of the set of rules created for the hospital selection mechanism:
        </para>
        <programlisting>
            
            rule "Select Closest Hospital"   
                ruleflow-group "hospital-selection"
                when
                    $pI: WorkflowProcessInstance()
                    $emergency: Emergency($type: type.name)
                    $selectedHospital: Hospital() from accumulate ($hospital: Hospital() 
                                                                    from externalEntities.getAllHospitals(), 
                                                                    hospitalDistanceCalculator(
                                                                        new HospitalDistanceCalculationData(
                                                                                $hospital, $emergency))
                                                                    )
                then
                    String callId = ((Call)$pI.getVariable("call")).getId();
                    //Send Hospital Selected Message
                    MessageFactory.sendMessage(
                                                new HospitalSelectedMessage(callId,
                                                $selectedHospital)
                                                );
            
            end
            
        </programlisting>
        <para>
            This basic rule calculates the closest hospital to the emergency location iterating the location of all 
            the available hospitals. The available hospitals are being dynamically calculated based on periodical 
            updates reports received in the central.
        </para>
        <para>
            The following business rule uses the temporal operators to analyze and react based on the patient´s 
            vital signs. Once the patient is inside the ambulance, all his/her vital signs are sent to the 
            central offices and monitored by a set of rules that are designed to analyze anomalous situations 
            and generate warnings. These warnings are automatic reactions executed by the system when a 
            specific pattern is found in multiple sources of real time events. These warnings can be used to 
            influence the hospital selection, the route to reach the selected hospital, or even trigger new 
            on-demand procedures. 
        </para> 
        <programlisting>
            rule "Patient heart attack pattern"
                when
                    ArrayList(size > 7 ) from collect( 
                    PulseEvent( processed == false, $pulse: value) over window:time(1s) 
                                                                    from entry-point "patientHeartbeats") 
                then
                    MessageFactory.sendMessage( new PatientMonitorAlertMessage(
                                                                 callId, vehicleId, 
                                                                "Warning, patient suffering a heart attack ", 
                                                                 new java.util.Date()));
            end
        </programlisting>
        <para>
            This simple rule evaluates in real time the events that are coming from a stream called “patientHeartBeats”. 
            If we find more than 7 events per second filtering the values of those particular events, we can say that 
            it is very likely that the patient is having a heart attack. The application provides a configurable module 
            that allows us to set up different devices to be used as input for these events.  We have designed a set of 
            bindings for the Wii Remote Control Accelerometer, the IPhone Accelerometer and Android Devices Accelerometers 
            that can be plugged as event sources.  Based on the values that are being sent by these devices, the rules 
            will react if a pattern is found. 
        </para>
    </section>
    
    <section>
        <title>Fire Emergency Procedure</title>
        <para>
            This procedure will be executed each time that the company needs to deal with a fire situation. 
            Once again, a set of business processes and business rules will compose this procedure.  For this 
            procedure, we will analyze a business process that describes a more dynamic set of activities that 
            needs to be executed.
        </para> 
        <figure>
            <title>Fire Emergency Procedure</title>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata fileref="images/DefaultFireEmergencyMultiTruckAdHoc.png" format="PNG"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        <para>
            This more unstructured process allows us to represent a situation where we send one or more fire trucks to a 
            fire emergency. Each truck will have a limited amount of water that can be recharged in the fire departments. 
            This process is being driven by the events that are being received in the central offices, which allow us to 
            coordinate if we need more trucks; or if the situation is under control, we can reduce the number of trucks 
            that we are using.
        </para>
        <para>
            For this procedure a set of rules is defined to control the water tanks and select the closest water provider; 
            a planning algorithm is also used to calculate the initial amount of trucks required to deal with the fire situation. 
        </para>
    </section>
</chapter>
