<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<chapter version="5.0"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook http://www.docbook.org/xml/5.0/xsd/docbook.xsd http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink http://www.docbook.org/xml/5.0/xsd/xlink.xsd"
         xml:base="./" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:ns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
    <title>Emergency Service - Knowledge Representation</title>
    <section>
        <title>Declarative Knowledge Representation</title>
        <para>
            The application uses the concept of procedure to define the set of business processes, 
            business rules and domain specific services that will be used to deal with an emergency. 
            We have defined a set of default procedures that describe the activities that can be executed 
            during specific emergencies. The “Default Heart Attack Procedure” can be used to drive a standard 
            set of activities that needs to be executed each time a person suffers a heart attack. The “Default 
            Fire Emergency Procedure” describes the same but for emergencies that include fire situations where we 
            need to coordinate the firefighters department in order to mitigate the dangerous situation 
            as soon as possible. 
        </para>
        <para>
            Both procedures set up the basic activities that the company needs to execute in each specific 
            situation, but in no way do they limit the company to add, remove or execute more activities in parallel.
        </para>
        <para>
            Before executing these procedures, the company needs to identify the context of the emergency by 
            executing a set of activities that were designed to pick up the initial information and find out 
            what is happening. These activities are contained in a Generic Emergency Procedure that is executed 
            each time the phone rings in the central offices. 
        </para>
      
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Generic Emergency Procedure</title>
        <para>This procedure will initiate the information about an emergency and is based on the initial information that 
            is being gathered by the phone operators of the company. Using this information, a suggestion mechanism based 
            on Business Rules will be in charge of suggesting the most appropriate, specific procedures out of all the 
            available procedures.   
            
            This generic procedure is driven by the following business process:
        </para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="../images/GenericEmergencyProcedure.png"/>
            </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
        <para>
            The Suggest Emergency Procedures activity inside this business process uses a set of rules to analyze the context 
            of the emergency gathered to suggest a set of procedures that fits with that specific situation. These rules will 
            evaluate the status of the company in order to suggest viable procedures. 
        </para>    
        <para>    
            Once the Suggestion rules are executed, the control expert in charge reviews the suggestions and modifies or 
            approves the selected procedures. The business process automatically will start each selected procedure in 
            parallel and it will wait until it receives a notification that all the specific procedures have ended. 
        </para>
        <para> 
            The main purpose of this generic procedure is to speed up the activities that need to be executed for every 
            emergency that the central offices handle. The suggestion rules help the experts by giving them a clear 
            set of procedures that can be executed based on the current status of the company and also on the contextual 
            and semantic information gathered for each specific situation. Once the procedures are started, a separate 
            group of resources will be used to monitor all the activities executed for each emergency.
        </para>
        
    </section>

</chapter>
