<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<chapter version="5.0"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook http://www.docbook.org/xml/5.0/xsd/docbook.xsd http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink http://www.docbook.org/xml/5.0/xsd/xlink.xsd"
         xml:base="./" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:ns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
    <title>Emergency Service Model</title>
    <section>
        <title>Introduction</title>
        <para>
            The Emergency Service Model module contains all the entities definitions that the application will use. All
            the data structures that will be used to exchange information between the different modules, all the information
            that we want to persist to keep the status of the application and all the definitions that can reused by all the 
            other modules will be included here.            
        </para>
        <para>
            The following sections will introduce the most important entities described inside this module as well as some helpers 
            which were included here to keep the project structure simple.
        </para>
        
        <para>
            The model module contains all the definitions and vocabulary that will be used across all the layers of the application. 
            This module contains all the data structures that need to be persisted and all the other modules include this project 
            as a dependency. 
        </para>
    </section>
       
    <section>
        <title>Packages</title>
        <para>
            
        
        </para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Entities</title>
        <para>
            
        
        </para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Services Helpers</title>
        <para>
            This component will be in charge of allowing us to attach different activities and 
            entities to a specific emergency. This tracking component will allows us to scope information 
            for each specific emergency. 
            
            Some of the methods that this service will expose are:

        </para>
        <programlisting>
            //Creation
            public String newCallId();
            
            public String newEmergencyId();
            
            ...
            
            //Attach
            public void attachEmergency(String callId, String emergencyId);
            
            ...
            
            //Detach
            public void detachEmergency(String emergencyId);
            
            //Query
            public String getCallAttachedToEmergency(String emergencyId);
        </programlisting>
        <para>
            This service should also bring a domain specific query interface that allows us to retrieve the information for
            each specific emergency and all the relationships with all the attached entities and services.
        </para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Work Item Handlers</title>
        <para>
            
        
        </para>
    </section>
   

</chapter>
